Well somewhere banking authorities are showing
belief in the potential of cryptocurrency
and somewhere else, cryptocurrency seems to
be losing it’s only stability, it’s peg
again and again.
Hello everyone and welcome back to coinmonks,
this is Shambhavi with you again for another
fresh dose to new updates.
Starting up with the headlines,
Kazakhstan’s Central Bank Chairman Believes
in the Potential of Cryptocurrency
Stablecoins Loses Peg Yet Again
Prudential Insurance is all set to Plan a
Crypto Push
UK to Test Blockchain Technology in Traditional
Market Activities.
Starting up,The National Bank of Kazakhstan’s
Chairman, Galymzhan Pirmatov, says that it
aims to extract the profit from technologies
the cryptocurrency market could provide.
He made the statements during a press conference
on June 7.
The Chairman, who stated that the bank is
eager to explore the possibilities and potential
of crypto, says,” I don’t think that the
National Bank is a latecomer.
Like many other banks and financial regulators
across the globe, we’re watching closely
and researching the question(crypto potential).”
Kazakhstan’s Central Bank Chairman Believes
in the Potential of Cryptocurrency
While emphasising that Kazakhstan’s central
bank wants to extract the maximum profit from
the innovative potential crypto offers, Primatov
pointed out that it is too early to speak
about crypto legalisation.
While he commented on the reservations about
the risks to macroeconomic stability, Primates
also re emphasised that the bank is not going
to ignore the crypto market ecosystem.
His statements come against the backdrop of
the National Bank’s ongoing central bank
digital currency (CBDC) project.
The National Bank of Kazakhstan had earlier
said it plans to present the results of the
CBDC study to stakeholders in July 2022.
According to sources, the bank plans to announce
its methodology on a digital tenge by June
end.
The final decision on implementing the central
bank digital currency will reportedly be made
in accordance with that methodology before
the end of 2022.
In May this year, the Kazakhstan parliament
made amendments to the national tax code which
suggested connecting a crypto mining tax tied
to the electricity prices consumed by mining
entities.
Kazakhstan is one of the largest mining markets
in the world and generated approximately $1.5
million of state earnings from mining in Q1
2022.
Next up, The value of the stablecoins, USDT
and USDC, falls by a significant amount.Earlier
in May, UST lost its peg twice, and its value
dropped by 56% in 24 hours.
It raised questions in the market about the
stability that these stablecoins actually
have.
It was followed by Luna’s downfall when
the currency lost almost 99% of its value.
Stablecoins Loses Peg Yet Again
On June 6, a similar event occurred on the
Oasis Network when USDT and USDC de-pegged,
and their value fell to $0.12.
The price of USDT could only bounce back to
$0.51, but USDC’s price went up to $0.98.
This downfall has caused tension among the
users, and a few have questioned the suspicious
fall in the value of the stablecoins only
in the Oasis network.
The Oasis is a blockchain platform that is
privacy-enabled for open finance.
According to the data collected from DeFi
Llama, the TVL of the Oasis network plummeted
from $214.25m to $67.41m.
The downfall began on June 4.
Many are guessing that the lack of liquidity
could be the cause of the crash.
In the last 24 hours, the value of the protocol
has gone down by 45.67%.
And now moving onto our next update, Multiple
blockchain utilization instances are being
incorporated in the banking industry right
now, varying from customer-facing payment
technology to trading and exchange services.
While the insurance sector lags behind banking
in terms of technology adoption, it is distinctively
placed to profit from blockchain technology.
Prudential Insurance is all set to Plan a
Crypto Push
Prudential Financial, the American Fortune
Global 500 and Fortune 500 subsidiary companies
that offer insurance, planning for retirement,
investment management, and other services,
has lodged ten trademark applications to enter
the metaverse and the realm of non-fungible
tokens (NFTs).
The insurer filed ten trademark applications
with the United States Patent and Trademark
Office relating to NFTs, cryptocurrencies,
and blockchain technology (USPTO).
Prudential’s iconic “The Rock,” asset
management subsidiary PGIM, its ticker “PRU,”
and the Rock logo have all registered trademark
applications.
Prudential has been experimenting with blockchain
technology for a long time.
The trademark applications for NFTs, cryptocurrencies,
and the metaverse, on the other hand, demonstrate
the company’s interest in cutting-edge technologies.
As crypto adoption grows, the company’s
standpoint on digital assets has shifted.
Michael Kondoudis, a trademark attorney, announced
the news on Twitter earlier today.
Prudential Insurance will also offer virtual
insurance and financial services for the metaverse
and virtual worlds.
The hype surrounding the metaverse has attracted
a slew of businesses, celebrities, and investors.
According to the filling, Prudential will
be covering:
* Financial transaction services involving
cryptocurrency, NFTS +blockchain technology.
* Virtual insurance and financial services
for the metaverse + virtual environments.
* Providing financial information about decentralized
finance, NFTS + digital, virtual, and Cryptocurrencies.
Many existing insurance companies face competitive
challenges, such as poor customer involvement,
slow growth in established markets, and digitization
trends, which blockchain can resolve.
By automating critical functions, the most
encouraging insurance-related use cases can
be, enabling growth, increasing effectiveness,
and lowering costs.
And now winding up with one last coverage
for today,The United Kingdom is expected to
begin live testing blockchain technology for
conventional marketing operations such as
stock and bond trading and settlement as part
of an attempt to become a global “crypto
hub.”
UK to Test Blockchain Technology in Traditional
Market Activities.
Utilizing distributed ledger technology (DLT),
which facilitates crypto assets, is a major
objective for making finance market infrastructure
more inventive and effective for users, as
per Gwyneth Nurse, the ministry’s director-general
for financial services.
Nurse says the UK plans to develop a “sandbox”
for testing DLT projects within its financial
sector infrastructure next year.
“The government might also want to see if
trading and settlement can be combined.”
A sandbox will enable market participants
to try out new regulatory best practices and
make structural changes, Nurse said at the
annual IDX derivatives conference in London.
This is a framework that the UK government
spearheaded in terms of developing fintech
companies.
A sandbox, for example, is a testing environment
for projects that involve real clients.
Nurse stated that the finance ministry and
the Bank of England will collectively analyze
a digital pound later this year, following
a second consultation process.
A digital pound would not be accessible until
the second half of the next decade, according
to Nurse, if a central bank digital currency
is authorized.